fortive.com 2019-04-26

# F

                                                                                                   [GDPR Programme]
                                                                                                        [22 May 2018]
                                                  FORTIVE CORPORATION
                                                     PRIVACY NOTICE
THIS PRIVACY NOTICE APPLIES ONLY TO SITUATIONS WHERE THE GENERAL DATA PROTECTION REGULATION (GDPR) AND RELATED
EUROPEAN DATA PROTECTION LAWS GOVERN THE WAY FORTIVE HANDLES, OR “PROCESSES”, YOUR PERSONAL DATA. THESE LAWS
ARE MOST LIKELY TO APPLY WHENEVER A COMPANY IS ESTABLISHED IN EUROPE OR HANDLES THE PERSONAL DATA OF INDIVIDUALS
WHO ARE LOCATED IN EUROPE.
THIS NOTICE DOES NOT APPLY TO OUR HANDLING OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA IN THE HUMAN RESOURCES CONTEXT. A SEPARATE
PRIVACY NOTICE APPLIES TO THESE SITUATIONS AND IS AVAILABLE FROM THE FORTIVE CORPORATE HUMAN RESOURCES
DEPARTMENT.
IF THIS NOTICE DOES APPLY TO HOW FORTIVE HANDLES YOUR PERSONAL DATA, PLEASE READ IT CAREFULLY BECAUSE IT PROVIDES
IMPORTANT INFORMATION AND EXPLAINS YOUR RIGHTS. IF THIS NOTICE DOES NOT APPLY TO HOW WE PROCESS YOUR PERSONAL
DATA AND YOU HAVE RELATED QUESTIONS OR CONCERNS, WE INVITE YOU TO CONTACT US BY ANY OF THE METHODS LISTED AT THE
BOTTOM OF THIS DOCUMENT.
  Who are we?
  We are Fortive Corporation, with headquarters at 6920 Seaway Boulevard in Everett, Washington 98203,
  USA (“Fortive”).
  We provide essential technology for the people who accelerate progress. This Privacy Notice explains how
  we use the personal data we hold on you as a current, former, or future customer, distributor, investor,
  creditor, advisor, website visitor, supplier, service provider, vendor, and the like.
  We may use your information jointly with our affiliated operating companies worldwide. An updated list of
  these operating companies is available here.
  We will be the “controllers” of the personal data you provide to us. We and our operating companies
  publish similar Privacy Notices and, as explained below, together we will provide you full details on where
  your personal data is located and how it is processed.
  What does this Privacy Notice cover?
  We at Fortive take your personal data seriously. This policy:
  •    sets out the types of personal data that we collect about you;
  •    explains how and why we collect and use your personal data;
  •    explains how long we keep your personal data for;
  •    explains when, why and with who we will share your personal data;
  •    sets out the legal basis we have for using your personal data;
  •    explains the effect of refusing to provide the personal data requested;
  •    explains where we store your personal data and whether we transfer your data outside of the European
       Economic Area;
  •    explains the different rights and choices you have when it comes to your personal data; and
  •    explains how you can contact us.
                                                                                                               Page 1

                                                                                                   [GDPR Programme]
                                                                                                       [22 May 2018]
                                                FORTIVE CORPORATION
                                                  PRIVACY NOTICE
What personal data do we collect about you?
Over the course of our interactions, it is routine for us to collect and process certain personal information
about you. This information includes your name, date of birth, contact and financial details, product and
service preferences, how you use our websites, and information collected using CCTV cameras (only if you
visit one of our premises that uses this technology).
In exceptional cases we may also collect and process sensitive personal data about you, but only where we
inform you in advance and you have given us your explicit consent.
Where do we collect personal data about you from?
We may collect personal data about you from the following sources:
•     Directly from you. This is information you provide to us.
•     From an agent or third party acting on your behalf, such as a distributor, one of our affiliated operating
      companies, a lead referral service, or a data provider who collected information from you directly or
      indirectly.
•     Through publicly available sources, such as LinkedIn or even by word of mouth.
•     Using CCTV cameras. Where we have cameras on our premises, your image and movements will be
      recorded.
How and why do we use your personal data?
We use your personal data for the following purposes:
•     to contact you to discuss the services or products you receive from us and any changes to them;
•     to respond to any questions or concerns you have raised;
•     to deal with administrative matters such as invoicing and renewal
•     to otherwise carry out our obligations arising under our contract with you and to enforce the same;
•     to carry out anti-money laundering and other compliance checks and controls; and
•     to verify your identity;
We will not use your information for any other unrelated purposes unless we are required to do so by law.
How long do we keep your personal data?
How long we keep your information will depend on the purpose for which we use it.
We only keep your information for as long as is reasonably necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy
Notice or, if longer, as required by applicable law or regulation. We have internal rules that set out how long
we retain information. What this means in practice will vary as between different types of information, and
when we consider our approach we take into account any ongoing need for the information as well as our
                                                                                                              Page 2

                                                                                                   [GDPR Programme]
                                                                                                       [22 May 2018]
                                                FORTIVE CORPORATION
                                                    PRIVACY NOTICE
legal obligations, for example in relation to tax, health and safety, and potential or actual disputes or
investigations.
Who do we share your personal data with?
From time to time your personal data may be shared with third parties such our professional advisers,
service providers, group companies, and corporate transactional (mergers and acquisitions) partners and
advisors for the following purposes.
•    Professional advisers: including accountancy and legal firms where they require that information in
     order to provide Fortive with advice;
•    Service providers: including those organisations who provide and support our data management and
     storage systems;
•    Group companies: Fortive is a member of a global organisation, and data may be shared internally
     within the group, primarily for business and operational purposes.
•    Merger partners: it may be that Fortive or any of its affiliates merges or is acquired by a separate
     organisation, in which case it will become necessary to share personal data with them.
All of these third parties are bound to comply with similar and equally stringent undertakings of privacy and
confidentiality.
Where required we share your personal information with third parties to comply with a legal obligation;
when we believe in good faith that an applicable law requires it; at the request of governmental authorities
conducting an investigation; to detect and protect against fraud, or any technical or security vulnerabilities;
to respond to an emergency; or otherwise to protect the rights, property, safety, or security of third parties,
visitors to our websites, our businesses, or the public.
No other third parties have access to your information unless we specifically say so in this Privacy Notice, or
the law requires this.
What legal basis do we have for using your personal data?
We process your information:
•    to be able to provide you with products and services in line with our Terms & Conditions and the other
     information provided via Fortive websites.
•    as this is necessary for the performance of the contract with you or to take steps at your request prior
     to entering into this contract.
•    to comply with our legal obligations.
•    to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of others.
•    as this is necessary in pursuit of our legitimate interests in operating a global business, and this includes
     profiling related to your personal data. While there are some risks inherent in any processing of
     personal data, we have considered the risk to your data protection rights and on balance determined it
     is outweighed by the significant benefits in providing Fortive’s goods and services to a relevant and
     interested marketplace. We’ve also implemented processes and controls to protect your rights. You
     have the right to object, on grounds relating to your particular situation, at any time to processing of
                                                                                                               Page 3

                                                                                               [GDPR Programme]
                                                                                                    [22 May 2018]
                                             FORTIVE CORPORATION
                                                PRIVACY NOTICE
    personal data concerning you which is based on legitimate interests. More information on this right and
    on how to exercise it is set out below.
•   for health or disability requirements that you or others provide about you. In such cases we always ask
    for your consent before undertaking such processing and you have the right to withdraw your consent
    at any time. More information on this right and how to exercise it is set out below.
•   On the basis of your consent for us to process your personal data for a particular purpose.
What happens if you do not provide us with the information we request or ask that we stop processing your
information?
We sometimes have statutory and contractual obligations that require us to process your information. If you
don’t provide the information requested, we may not be able to fulfil our contract with you or perform our
obligations to you or related others.
Do we make solely automated decisions concerning you?
No, we do not carry out solely automated decision making or automated profiling.
Do we use Cookies to collect personal data on you?
To provide better service to you on our websites, we and our service providers use cookies to collect your
personal data when you browse. For information about our use of cookies and how to decline them or turn
them off please read our cookie notice available when visiting one of our websites.
What about marketing?
Fortive and its operating companies would like to contact you from time to time about our new similar
products and promotional offers by email, text message, telephone, and mail.
Where we have already collected valid marketing permissions from you, you can always unsubscribe or opt
out of our marketing communications, at any time, by clicking the “Unsubscribe” link in any of our
communications or by contacting us using the details at the end of this Privacy Notice.
Where do we store your personal data? Do we transfer your personal data outside the EEA?
We store your personal data safely at our premises, in contracted storage facilities, with our service
providers, or on our servers within the country where we are based and otherwise within the European
Economic Area (EEA).
We strive to process your information within the country where we collected it or within the EEA. If we or
our service providers transfer personal data, where relevant, outside of the EEA, we will always require that
appropriate safeguards are in place to protect the information that is transferred. For example, a portion of
                                                                                                           Page 4

                                                                                                    [GDPR Programme]
                                                                                                         [22 May 2018]
                                                FORTIVE CORPORATION
                                                   PRIVACY NOTICE
our centralised Compliance, Marketing, and Finance functions are performed outside of the EEA, in the USA,
so we have put in place safeguards to protect personal data exported from the EEA that is processed in or
accessed from the USA. You can obtain a copy of the safeguards in place for such transfers by contacting us
using the details at the end of this Privacy Notice.
How do we keep your personal data secure?
We ensure the security of your personal data by implementing a specific set of technical and organisational
security measures that are based on controls published by the Center for Internet Security. These controls
call for the use of encryption, firewalls, and other measures that ensure we provide a level of security
appropriate to the risk presented by a particular situation.
What rights do you have in relation to the personal data we hold on you?
By law, you have a number of rights when it comes to your personal data. We describe them below.
Further information and advice about your rights can be obtained from the data protection regulator in
your country.
Rights                                         What does this mean?
 1. The right to be informed                  You have the right to be provided with clear, transparent and
                                              easily understandable information about how we use your
                                              information and your rights. This is why we’re providing you with
                                              the information in this Privacy Notice.
 2. The right of access                       You have the right to obtain access to your information (if we’re
                                              processing it), and certain other information (similar to that
                                              provided in this Privacy Notice).
                                              This is so you’re aware and can check that we’re using your
                                              information in accordance with data protection law.
 3. The right to rectification                You are entitled to have your information corrected if it’s
                                              inaccurate or incomplete.
 4. The right to erasure                      This is also known as ‘the right to be forgotten’ and, in simple
                                              terms, enables you to request the deletion or removal of your
                                              information where there’s no compelling reason for us to keep
                                              using it. This is not a general right to erasure; there are
                                              exceptions.
 5. The right to restrict processing          You have rights to ‘block’ or suppress further use of your
                                              information. When processing is restricted, we can still store
                                              your information, but may not use it further. We keep lists of
                                              people who have asked for further use of their information to be
                                              ‘blocked’ to make sure the restriction is respected in future.
                                                                                                                Page 5

                                                                                                  [GDPR Programme]
                                                                                                      [22 May 2018]
                                              FORTIVE CORPORATION
                                                 PRIVACY NOTICE
Rights                                       What does this mean?
 6. The right to data portability           You have rights to obtain and reuse your personal data for your
                                            own purposes across different services. For example, if you
                                            decide to switch to a new provider, this enables you to move,
                                            copy or transfer your information easily between our IT systems
                                            and theirs safely and securely, without affecting its usability.
 7. The right to object to processing       You have the right to object to certain types of processing,
                                            including processing based on our legitimate interests and
                                            processing for direct marketing (i.e. if you no longer want to be
                                            contacted with potential opportunities).
 8. The right to lodge a complaint          You have the right to lodge a complaint about the way we handle
                                            or process your personal data with your national data protection
                                            regulator.
 9. The right to withdraw consent           If you have given your consent to anything we do with your
                                            personal data, you have the right to withdraw your consent at
                                            any time (although if you do so, it does not mean that anything
                                            we have done with your personal data with your consent up to
                                            that point is unlawful). This includes your right to withdraw
                                            consent to us using your personal data for marketing purposes.
How can you make a request to exercise your rights?
To exercise any of the rights above, or to ask a question, contact us using the details set out at the end of
this Privacy Notice.
How will we handle a request to exercise your rights?
We’ll respond as soon as we can, generally within one month from when we receive your request. If we
expect your request is going to take us longer to fulfil, we’ll come back to you within that first month and let
you know.
We usually act on requests and provide information free of charge, but we may charge a reasonable fee to
cover our administrative costs of providing the information for baseless or excessive/repeated requests and
requests for further copies of the same information. Alternatively, the law may allow us to refuse to act on
such requests.
How can you contact us?
If you have questions on the processing of your personal data, would like to exercise any of your rights, or
are unhappy with how we’ve handled your information, please contact us here: Investor Relations, 6920
Seaway Boulevard, Everett, Washington, 98203, USA, or investors@fortive.com.
                                                                                                             Page 6

                                                                                               [GDPR Programme]
                                                                                                   [22 May 2018]
                                              FORTIVE CORPORATION
                                                 PRIVACY NOTICE
If you’re not satisfied with our response to any complaint or believe our processing of your information
does not comply with data protection law, you can also make a complaint to the data protection regulator
in your country.
                                                                                                          Page 7
